<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">PianoMeter</string>
    <string name="action_delete_inharmonicity_for_current_note">Delete inharmonicity for current note</string>
    <string name="action_paste">Paste</string>
    <string name="action_reset_measured_pitch_data">Reset measured pitch data</string>
    <string name="action_set">Set</string>
    <string name="action_clear">Clear</string>
    <string name="action_apply">Apply</string>
    <string name="action_default">Default</string>
    <string name="action_restore_defaults">Restore defaults</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="symbol_cents" translatable="false">&#xA2;</string>
    <string name="symbol_hertz" translatable="false">Hz</string>
    <string name="activity_adjust_weights_title">Tuning Style (Interval Weights)</string>
    <string name="activity_calibrate_title">Calibration</string>
    <string name="activity_files_action_add">Add</string>
    <string name="activity_files_action_export">Export</string>
    <string name="activity_files_action_load">Load</string>
    <string name="activity_files_action_more">More</string>
    <string name="activity_files_action_rename">Rename</string>
    <string name="action_save">Save</string>
    <string name="activity_files_action_select">Select</string>
    <string name="activity_files_action_select_all">All</string>
    <string name="activity_files_action_select_none">None</string>
    <string name="activity_files_action_sort">Sort</string>
    <string name="activity_files_dialog_file_already_exists_message">File already exists. Overwrite?</string>
    <string name="activity_files_dialog_rename_file_title">Rename to</string>
    <string name="activity_files_error_delete_no_files_selected">No file selected</string>
    <string name="activity_files_error_exporting_file">Error exporting tuning file</string>
    <string name="activity_files_error_exporting_file_format">Error exporting file: %s</string>
    <string name="activity_files_message_file_exported">Tuning file exported</string>
    <string name="activity_files_no_tunings">You haven\'t tuned any pianos yet.\nCreate new tuning file to start tuning a piano</string>
    <string name="activity_files_overwrite_option_keep_existing">Keep existing versions</string>
    <string name="activity_files_overwrite_option_replace_existing">Overwrite existing versions</string>
    <string name="activity_files_share_dialog_title">Share File</string>
    <string name="activity_files_sort_dialog_title">Sort by</string>
    <string name="activity_files_sort_order_make_default">Make default</string>
    <string name="activity_global_settings_title">Settings</string>
    <string name="activity_help_title">Help</string>
    <string name="activity_load_tuning_style_title">Load Tuning Style</string>
    <string name="activity_load_tuning_temperament_title">Load Temperament</string>
    <string name="activity_main_chart_fft_spectrum">Frequency spectrum</string>
    <string name="activity_main_chart_inharmonicity">Inharmonicity</string>
    <string name="activity_main_chart_tuning_curve">Tuning curve</string>
    <string name="activity_main_exit_pitch_raise">EXIT PITCH RAISE</string>
    <string name="activity_main_note_switching_automatic">Automatic note switching</string>
    <string name="activity_main_note_switching_disabled">Automatic note switching disabled</string>
    <string name="activity_main_note_switching_stepwise">Stepwise note switching</string>
    <string name="activity_main_spectrum_chart">Spectrum Chart</string>
    <string name="activity_main_start_pitch_raise">START PITCH RAISE</string>
    <string name="activity_open_tuning_file_title">Open tuning file</string>
    <string name="activity_tuning_file_settings_title">Tuning file settings</string>
    <string name="activity_tuning_style_action_new_tuning">New</string>
    <string name="activity_tuning_style_action_undo">Undo</string>
    <string name="activity_tuning_style_action_use_cents">Use cents</string>
    <string name="activity_tuning_style_action_use_hertz">Use Hertz</string>
    <string name="activity_tuning_styles_rename_tuning_style_dialog_title">Rename tuning style</string>
    <string name="activity_tuning_temperament_title">Temperament</string>
    <string name="activity_upgrade_action_subscribe_to_pro">Subscribe to Pro</string>
    <string name="activity_upgrade_action_upgrade_to_plus">Upgrade to Plus</string>
    <string name="activity_upgrade_action_upgrade_to_pro">Upgrade to Pro</string>
    <string name="activity_upgrade_active_plan_plus">Plus version active</string>
    <string name="activity_upgrade_active_plan_pro">Pro version active</string>
    <string name="activity_upgrade_app_billing_unavailable">Oops! There is a problem with in-app billing. Try again later!</string>
    <string name="activity_upgrade_awaiting_payment">Awaiting payment…</string>
    <string name="activity_upgrade_description_functionality_levels">PianoMeter has three levels of functionality: Free, Plus, and Professional.</string>
    <string name="activity_upgrade_error_cannot_fetch_inventory">Oops! There is a problem with getting the available upgrades. Try again later!</string>
    <string name="activity_upgrade_error_payment_system_not_ready">Payments system is not ready yet. Make sure you have the latest Google Play Services and reliable internet connection and try again.</string>
    <string name="activity_upgrade_error_purchase_failed">Oops! There was a problem with your purchase. Make sure you have the latest Google Play Services and reliable internet connection and try again.</string>
    <string name="activity_upgrade_error_purchase_verification_failed">Oops! Your purchase could not be verified. Make sure you have the latest Google Play Services and reliable internet connection and try again.</string>
    <string name="activity_upgrade_has_pending_purchase">Please wait for the previous purchase to complete</string>
    <string name="activity_upgrade_message_one_time_purchase_format">One time purchase of %1$s</string>
    <string name="activity_upgrade_price_loading">Loading…</string>
    <string name="activity_upgrade_product_not_found">Product not found</string>
    <string name="activity_upgrade_title">Upgrade</string>
    <string name="billing_period_one_month">paid monthly</string>
    <string name="billing_period_one_week">paid weekly</string>
    <string name="billing_period_one_year">paid yearly</string>
    <string name="billing_period_six_months">paid every 6 months</string>
    <string name="billing_period_three_months">paid every 3 months</string>
    <string name="dialog_change_inharmonicity_weight_factor_message">Adjust the weight ratio for individual inharmonicity measurements vs. the best fit average inharmonicity curve. Decreasing this value will make the tuning curve look smoother, but the tuning targets won\'t align as well with the spacing of harmonics. (Default: 0.75)</string>
    <string name="dialog_change_inharmonicity_weight_factor_title">Inharmonicity weight factor</string>
    <string name="dialog_change_interval_weight_value_title">Change interval weight</string>
    <string name="dialog_change_maximum_overpull_message">Maximum overshoot to avoid breaking strings during pitch raise:</string>
    <string name="dialog_change_maximum_overpull_title">Maximum overshoot</string>
    <string name="dialog_pitch_raise_overshoot_factor_message">This multiplier can force more or less overshoot during a pitch raise. For example, increasing this to 1.25 would increase the calculated overshoot by 25%. (Default: 1.00)</string>
    <string name="dialog_pitch_raise_overshoot_factor_title">Pitch Raise Overshoot Factor</string>
    <string name="dialog_highest_midsection_title">Select the highest note in the midsection</string>
    <string name="dialog_lowest_unwound_title">Select the note with the lowest unwound (plain wire) strings</string>
    <string name="dialog_note_names_title">Note Names</string>
    <string name="dialog_piano_type_title">Please select the piano type</string>
    <string name="dialog_pitch_error_no_keys_selected">Select at least one key!</string>
    <string name="dialog_pitch_raise_title">Pitch raise</string>
    <string name="dialog_reference_frequency_error_only_digits_allowed">Enter only digits!</string>
    <string name="dialog_reference_frequency_message">Enter new frequency (Hz):</string>
    <string name="dialog_reference_frequency_title">Adjust reference frequency</string>
    <string name="dialog_show_in_info_box_title">Show in info box</string>
    <string name="evaluation_version_popup_message">NOTE: The \"free\" version of this app is primarily for evaluation, and it only allows you to tune notes on the piano between C3 and C5. To tune the entire piano you will need to buy an upgrade through an in-app purchase.</string>
    <string name="message_cents">Cents:</string>
    <string name="message_frequency">Frequency:</string>
    <string name="message_migration_running">Migrating tuning files</string>
    <string name="message_temperament_saved">Temperament saved</string>
    <string name="message_tuning_style_implemented">Style implemented as global default and applied to current tuning</string>
    <string name="message_unsaved_tuning_style_changes">You have unsaved changes. Save changes before exit?</string>
    <string name="pitch_raise_pre_measurement_hint">Measure pitch of the selected notes, then press \"START PITCH RAISE\"</string>
    <string name="pitch_raise_setup_note">Select up to 4 notes to measure the current pitch in each octave</string>
    <string name="backups_frequency_daily">Daily</string>
    <string name="backups_frequency_monthly">Monthly</string>
    <string name="backups_frequency_never">Never</string>
    <string name="backups_frequency_weekly">Weekly</string>
    <string name="backups_frequency_yearly">Yearly</string>
    <string name="backups_notification_backup_failed">An error occurred while performing tuning file backup</string>
    <string name="dropbox_action_connect">Connect</string>
    <string name="dropbox_action_disconnect">Disconnect</string>
    <string name="dropbox_backups_list_title">Backup Files</string>
    <string name="dropbox_error_message_no_internet_connection">You\'re not connected to the Internet</string>
    <string name="dropbox_message_backup_failed">Backup completed with error</string>
    <string name="dropbox_message_backup_now">Backup Now</string>
    <string name="dropbox_message_backup_restored_successfully">Piano tunings successfully restored</string>
    <string name="dropbox_message_backup_successfull">Tuning file backup completed successfully</string>
    <string name="dropbox_message_backup_to_dropbox">Backup to Dropbox</string>
    <string name="dropbox_message_connected">You\'re connected to Dropbox</string>
    <string name="dropbox_message_failed_to_load_list_of_backups">Error loading list of backup files. Please check your internet connection and try again.</string>
    <string name="dropbox_message_last_backup">Last Backup: %s</string>
    <string name="dropbox_message_last_backup_never">Never</string>
    <string name="dropbox_message_loading_backup_files">Loading…</string>
    <string name="dropbox_message_not_connected">You\'re not connected to Dropbox</string>
    <string name="dropbox_message_performing_backup">Performing backup…</string>
    <string name="dropbox_message_restore_from_backup_failed">Failed to restore piano tunings</string>
    <string name="dropbox_message_restoring_backup">Restoring piano tunings…</string>
    <string name="dropbox_restore_dialog_title">How to restore backup?</string>
    <string name="dropbox_restore_strategy_missing">Only add missing tuning files</string>
    <string name="dropbox_restore_strategy_overwrite_all">Replace all tuning files</string>
    <string name="dropbox_restore_strategy_overwrite_existing">Add all tuning files, overwriting duplicates</string>
    <string name="error_cannot_load_tuning_style">Cannot load tuning style, reverting to default</string>
    <string name="error_device_not_supported">This audio sample rate of this device is not sufficient for the frequency range of a piano, or is not supported. Please use a different device.</string>
    <string name="error_migration_failed">Migration failed. Please try again</string>
    <string name="error_name_cannot_be_empty">Name cannot be empty</string>
    <string name="error_no_internet_connection">No internet connection. Please connect to the internet before proceeding</string>
    <string name="error_not_a_number">Not a valid number</string>
    <string name="error_temperament_not_found">Temperament not found. Tuning file restored with Equal temperament</string>
    <string name="purchase_error_format">Error purchasing: %1$s. Please check your internet connection and try again.</string>
    <string name="action_cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="action_continue">Continue</string>
    <string name="action_general_loading">Loading…</string>
    <string name="action_ok">OK</string>
    <string name="activity_files_action_copy">Copy</string>
    <string name="activity_files_action_delete">Delete</string>
    <string name="activity_files_action_search">Search</string>
    <string name="dimension_cents">cents</string>
    <string name="dropbox_action_retry">Retry</string>
    <string name="menu_files_option_rename">Rename</string>
    <string name="unsaved_changes_action_discard">Discard</string>
    <string name="unsaved_changes_action_save">Save</string>
    <string name="help_section_calibration_content">The internal clock inside most modern devices is accurate enough calibration should not be necessary, however you can calibrate the device to an external reference by accessing the calibration page from the main menu. To calibrate, first enter the calibration source frequency in the box, then while playing the calibration tone, toggle the calibration offset until the spinner stops. This calibration will then be saved until the app is uninstalled from your device.\n\nNote that because PianoMeter uses multi-partial tuning and expects tones with significant inharmonicity, testing the calibration outside of the calibration page will not work if the reference tone has any harmonics other than the fundamental 440 Hz frequency.</string>
    <string name="help_section_calibration_title">Calibration</string>
    <string name="help_section_getting_started_content">Quick start steps for tuning a piano:\n\n1. <b>Create a new tuning file</b> (Menu ➔ New tuning file) or load a saved file (pro version only).\n\n2. <b>Sample inharmonicity</b> to create a tuning curve. Play several notes across the range of the piano, playing each note for approximately 2 seconds. It is important to sample notes in the mid-section, tenor, and bass. The program is always listening and will automatically calculate an ideal tuning curve based on the inharmonicity of the sampled notes. Note: if the unisons are significantly out of tune you will get better and faster results by using mutes to isolate single strings.\n\n3. <b>Rough tuning</b> (optional): If the piano is more than about 10 cents sharp or flat you should do a rough tuning (“pitch adjustment” or “pitch raise”). Even if the piano is within ±3 cents of standard pitch it is still advisable to run through the notes quickly and fix any outliers, as this will result in a better fine tuning. The benefit of doing this pre-tuning pass is that the app will gather more inharmonicity data and further refine the tuning curve. If you skip this step you might consider quickly sampling inharmonicity for all the notes on the piano (except the treble) which takes less than 2 minutes.\n\n4. <b>Lock the tuning curve</b> using the “ear” button on the right. This stops further inharmonicity measurement and prevents the tuning curve from changing during a fine tuning.\n\n5. <b>Tune the piano.</b> The recommended order is to tune the midsection first, starting at the tenor break (often around D#3), tune up through the treble, and then tune the bass last.</string>
    <string name="help_section_getting_started_title">Getting started</string>
    <string name="help_section_graphing_area_content">There are 3 possible displays in the graphing area that can be accessed by swiping left or right or tapping on the left or right sides of the graph.\n\nThe primary graph plots the tuning curve or \"Railsback curve\" that shows the degree to which the tuning is stretched from pure octave equal temperament (which would be a flat horizontal line through the middle of the graph). However inharmonicity requires that we \"stretch\" the tuning of octaves slightly, resulting in the lower registers of the piano being tuned slightly flat and the upper registers being tuned slightly sharp. Whenever a note is played its pitch is plotted on the graph as a dot, allowing the user to see at a glance to see what the entire tuning looks like. For a perfectly in-tune piano, the dots will all fall exactly on tuning curve line. The vertical scale on the tuning curve graph goes from −50 to +50 cents.\n\nThe left graph shows the frequency spectrum from about 27 Hz (near the fundamental frequency of A0) to about 4300 Hz (near the frequency of C8). The frequencies are plotted on a logarithmic scale so that peaks in the spectrum align with their respective notes on the piano keyboard below. You will notice that most notes on the piano excite multiple peaks on the spectrum. These peaks correspond to the individual harmonics that make up each tone.\n\nThe right graph plots the measured inharmonicity of each note on the piano on a logarithmic scale. Inharmonicity is the degree to which the harmonics of a note are \"out of tune\" with the fundamental (lowest harmonic). The inharmonicity is a function of the length and stiffness of piano strings. Shorter and thicker strings have high inharmonicity, while longer or thinner strings have low inharmonicity. The inharmonicity affects the tuning of pianos, and each piano will be tuned differently because pianos are designed with different lengths of strings and sizes of wire. Also on the graph is a \"best fit\" line that is used to interpolate for notes that have not been measured yet, and to extrapolate to the top octave where inharmonicity is not measured.</string>
    <string name="help_section_graphing_area_title">Graphing area</string>
    <string name="help_section_locking_a_tuning_title">Locking a tuning</string>
    <string name="help_section_locking_tuning_content">By default, whenever the app is running it will be listening for and measuring the inharmonicity of each note. As new information is acquired it repeatedly recalculates the tuning in order to give the best tuning based on all available data. Generally the changes in tuning are quite small after the initial inharmonicity measurements of several notes across the range of the piano. However, it may be desirable to at some point “lock” a tuning to protect it from any future changes. This is achieved by toggling the button on the right side of the screen from “Listen” mode to “Lock” mode. A good time to do this might be after a pitch adjustment, when the inharmonicity of most notes has been measured.</string>
    <string name="help_section_note_switching_content">There are 3 note switching modes available through a selector on the main screen.\n\n<u>Automatic</u> note switching allows the app to detect and jump to any note played on the keyboard.\n\n<u>Stepwise</u> note switching allows the note to step up and down a scale, but prevents longer range jumps. While tuning chromatically this mode will prevent octave jumps that sometimes occur during long sustains, or random jumps due to background noise.\n\n<u>Lock</u> mode will prevent all automatic switching, locking to the current note.\n\nIn all three modes you can always switch the note by half steps or octaves by tapping arrow buttons to the right and left of the center note display.</string>
    <string name="help_section_note_switching_title">Note switching</string>
    <string name="help_section_pitch_raise">Pitch raise</string>
    <string name="help_section_pitch_raise_content">A Pitch Raise (pro version only) is a rough pre-tuning for pianos that are very out of tune and need to be tuned in two passes. In a pitch raise you tune the piano slightly above pitch (overshoot) so when the large increase in string tension makes the piano go flat again it will be roughly in tune. To begin a pitch raise, open the Pitch Raise dialogue from the main menu, then select the type of piano you are tuning. (The overshoot profile is slightly different on grand pianos vs. uprights.)\n\nNext select the lowest unwound (plain wire) strings, and the highest string in the mid-section.\n\nFinally select up to 4 notes per octave to pre-measure for calculating the pitch raise overshoot. These notes must be at least a minor third (3 half-steps) apart to avoid measuring the wrong note in pianos that are more than 100 cents flat. Two notes per octave (for example A’s and D#s) is sufficient. Press “Continue” and then play each note for every octave on the piano until the corresponding dot in the graphing area stabilizes. It is not necessary to measure all notes in every octave. PianoMeter will interpolate and extrapolate.\n\nWhen you are satisfied that the initial pitch for each note is measured accurately, press the “Start Pitch Raise” button. The graphing area at the bottom will now show a black line representing the tuning curve and a green line representing the target overshoot. The dial at the top will also rotate for each note to indicate the overshoot, and the pitch targets for the strobe rings will be adjusted. When a note is in tune the strobe rings will stop and the needle will be pointing directly up (which will generally not be zero). For the tuning order, it is recommended to start tuning at the tenor break (bottom of the mid-section) and tune upward to the top of the piano, then tune the bass strings last, working downward from the tenor break. For example, if the lowest note in the mid-section is D#3, first tune from D#3 to C8, then from D3 to A0. Finally press “Exit Pitch Raise” and fine-tune the piano in a second pass.</string>
    <string name="help_section_saving_and_loading_tuning_files_content">In the pro version it is possible to save tuning files that store the inharmonicity and tuning curve for pianos. The tuning files can then be loaded at a later date to re-tune the same piano.\n\nAlthough tuning files are saved automatically, you can input a name and/or identifying information for each file. This is done via Menu ➔ Tuning file settings. There you can enter information about the manufacturer, model, serial number, type of piano, and the name of the piano’s owner (for professional tuners with multiple clients) and other miscellaneous information about the piano. This information is for piano identification only and does not affect the tuning curve.\n\nTo load a previously saved tuning file, go to Menu ➔ Load tuning file, and then simply select the tuning file you wish to load. Saved tuning files can be sorted by name, manufacturer, and date accessed; you can also locate tuning files using the search bar at the top of the screen.\n\nLong-pressing a tuning file brings up a special menu with options to copy, rename, delete, or \"share\" a tuning file (exporting it to email, messaging, dropbox, etc.)</string>
    <string name="help_section_saving_and_loading_tuning_files_title">Saving and loading tuning files</string>
    <string name="help_section_tuning_display_content">There are multiple ways to see whether a note is sharp or flat. The text in the center of the screen displays the note being played and how many “cents” sharp or flat it is. Surrounding the center circle are a series of spinning bars, similar to a stroboscopic tuner’s phase display, whose direction and speed indicate how out of tune a note is. Clockwise spinning means the note is sharp, while counter-clockwise indicates the note is flat. Each set of spinning bars represents a specific harmonic of the note being played, and small numbers in the lower right indicate which harmonics are being measured. If a harmonic is not present in the tone, the corresponding spinner will not be displayed. Finally there is a pointer with a non-linear scale that indicates how sharp or flat the note is, again in cents. (A cent equals a hundredth of a half step.)</string>
    <string name="help_section_tuning_display_title">Tuning display</string>
    <string name="help_section_tuning_other_frequencies_content">By default tunings will be calculated around the international A=440 Hz pitch standard. If you wish to tune to a frequency other than A=440, this is possible via the Tuning file settings page, where you can set an alternate frequency standard (eg. A=415 or A=442) or an offset in cents from A=440. Changing this only affects the current tuning. If you wish to set an alternate default pitch standard for tuning files, this can be done on the Calibration page.</string>
    <string name="help_section_tuning_style">Tuning styles (interval weights)</string>
    <string name="help_section_tuning_style_content">The tuning style can be customized by adjusting “weights” that are assigned to various slow-beating intervals. Intervals with higher weight will be tuned more pure than intervals with lower weight, but all intervals will be tempered slightly in the tuning calculation.\n\n • Octaves can be used to somewhat control the “stretch” of a tuning. A high 2:1 octave weight reduces the stretch overall, and the 10:5 octave weight greatly affects the stretch of the low bass.\n\n Pure 12ths (5th plus an octave) generally result in a balanced tuning, so by default the 12ths are given a high weight.\n\n 5ths and 4ths are tuned narrow and wide respectively, so adjusting their weights can somewhat alter the overall stretch.\n\n Double octaves tend to be important for the high treble.\n\n Triple octaves and 19ths help ensure the piano sounds consonant when large chords are played. Triple octaves affect the stretch throughout the piano, especially in the treble and bass.\n\n You can also manually add or subtract extra stretch in the treble or bass for a specified number of notes/octaves.\n\nThe graph shows a tuning curve in black, and the width of different octave types in blue for the calculated tuning. A positive value indicates that the interval is tuned wide of pure, and a negative value indicates an interval tuned narrow of pure. For example, the line for the 2:1 octave has a value of approximately +2.0 at “A4”. This means that the 2:1 A4-A5 octave is tuned approximately 2 cents (0.5 beats per second) wide. (The 4:2 A4-A5 octave is tuned very nearly pure.) The varying darkness of the blue lines are a rough indicator of the strength of that interval throughout the range of the piano. For example, the 2:1 octave is strong through the midsection of the piano and into the treble, but is weak in the bass because the fundamental (1st) and 2nd harmonics are absent in the tone of the lowest bass notes. By contrast, the 8:4 and 10:5 octaves are strongest in the tenor and bass regions. The strength of each interval also affects the weight it is given in the final calculation of the tuning curve.</string>
    <string name="help_section_tuning_to_frequencies_title">Tuning to frequencies other than A=440</string>
    <string name="menu_files_option_copy">Copy</string>
    <string name="menu_files_option_delete">Delete</string>
    <string name="menu_files_option_open">Open</string>
    <string name="menu_files_option_share">Share</string>
    <string name="menu_item_general_settings">General Settings</string>
    <string name="menu_item_help">Help</string>
    <string name="menu_item_manage_subscription">Manage subscriptions</string>
    <string name="menu_item_new_pitch_raise">New pitch raise</string>
    <string name="menu_item_new_tuning_file">New tuning file</string>
    <string name="menu_item_open_tuning_file">Open tuning file</string>
    <string name="menu_item_pitch_raise">Pitch raise</string>
    <string name="menu_item_resume_last_tuning">Resume last tuning</string>
    <string name="menu_item_tuning_file_settings">Tuning file settings</string>
    <string name="menu_item_upgrade">Upgrade</string>
    <string name="menu_option_export_share">Share</string>
    <string name="menu_option_export_to_file">Save to file</string>
    <string name="permission_action_cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="permission_action_grant">Allow</string>
    <string name="permission_audio_rationale">This app needs to record audio through the microphone</string>
    <string name="permission_audio_request_message">Please grant the Microphone permission in the app\'s permissions, then restart the app.</string>
    <string name="permission_storage_rationale">This app needs to access external storage for tuning file import/export</string>
    <string name="permission_storage_request_message">Please open your device settings and grant permission for this app to access storage, then restart the app.</string>
    <string name="global_settings_adjust_weights">Style (interval weights): %1$s</string>
    <string name="global_settings_language">Language</string>
    <string name="global_settings_appearance">Appearance</string>
    <string name="global_settings_appearance_auto">Auto</string>
    <string name="global_settings_appearance_dark">Dark</string>
    <string name="global_settings_appearance_light">Light</string>
    <string name="global_settings_appearance_custom">Custom</string>
    <string name="global_settings_backup_dropbox">Dropbox backup</string>
    <string name="global_settings_calibration">Calibration: %1$.2f cents</string>
    <string name="global_settings_global_pitch_offset">Global Pitch Offset</string>
    <string name="global_settings_global_pitch_offset_message">This will be applied to future new tuning files.</string>
    <string name="global_settings_group_display">Display</string>
    <string name="global_settings_group_other">Other</string>
    <string name="global_settings_group_tuning">Tuning</string>
    <string name="global_settings_hide_navigation_bar">Hide navigation bar</string>
    <string name="global_settings_inharmonicity_weight_factor">Inharmonicity weight factor: %1$.2f</string>
    <string name="global_settings_audio_input">Audio Input: %1$s</string>
    <string name="global_settings_pitch_raise_overshoot_factor">Pitch raise overshoot factor: %1$.2f</string>
    <string name="global_settings_maximum_overpull">Maximum overshoot: %d cents</string>
    <string name="global_settings_note_names">Note names</string>
    <string name="global_settings_prevent_sleep">Prevent sleep</string>
    <string name="global_settings_show_in_info_box">Show in info box: %1$s</string>
    <string name="global_settings_color_scheme">Color Scheme</string>
    <string name="dialog_audio_input_title">Audio Input</string>
    <string name="dialog_audio_input_option_built_in_mic">Prefer built-in mic</string>
    <string name="dialog_audio_input_option_external_wired_mic">Prefer external mic</string>
    <string name="dialog_audio_input_option_allow_bluetooth">Allow bluetooth mic</string>
    <string name="hz_format">%s Hz</string>
    <string name="info_box_label_clock">Clock</string>
    <string name="info_box_label_make">Make</string>
    <string name="info_box_label_model">Model</string>
    <string name="info_box_label_pitch_offset">Pitch Offset</string>
    <string name="interval_weights_double_octave">Double Octave</string>
    <string name="interval_weights_extra_bass_stretch">Extra Bass Stretch</string>
    <string name="interval_weights_extra_treble_stretch">Extra Treble Stretch</string>
    <string name="interval_weights_fifth">Fifth</string>
    <string name="interval_weights_fourth">Fourth</string>
    <string name="interval_weights_nineteenth">Nineteenth</string>
    <string name="interval_weights_octave">Octave</string>
    <string name="interval_weights_stretch_cents_per_octave">Cents Per Octave</string>
    <string name="interval_weights_stretch_octaves">Octaves</string>
    <string name="interval_weights_third">Third</string>
    <string name="interval_weights_triple_octave">Triple Octave</string>
    <string name="interval_weights_twelfth">Twelfth</string>
    <string name="note_switching_mode_auto">Auto</string>
    <string name="note_switching_mode_lock">Lock</string>
    <string name="note_switching_mode_step">Step</string>
    <string name="piano_type_baby_grand">Baby grand</string>
    <string name="piano_type_concert_grand">Concert grand</string>
    <string name="piano_type_console">Console</string>
    <string name="piano_type_full_upright">Full upright</string>
    <string name="piano_type_medium_grand">Medium grand</string>
    <string name="piano_type_other">Other</string>
    <string name="piano_type_spinet">Spinet</string>
    <string name="piano_type_studio_upright">Studio upright</string>
    <string name="pitch_offset_summary_cents">%1$.2f cents</string>
    <string name="pitch_offset_summary_hz">%1$.1f Hz</string>
    <string name="setting_tile_customer_name">Customer/Name:</string>
    <string name="setting_tile_lowest_unwound_string">Lowest unwound string:</string>
    <string name="setting_tile_make">Make:</string>
    <string name="setting_tile_model">Model:</string>
    <string name="setting_tile_notes">Notes:</string>
    <string name="setting_tile_pitch_offset">Pitch offset:</string>
    <string name="setting_tile_serial">Serial number:</string>
    <string name="setting_tile_temperament">Temperament:</string>
    <string name="setting_tile_tuning_style">Style:</string>
    <string name="setting_tile_type">Type:</string>
    <string name="sort_property_date">Date</string>
    <string name="sort_property_manufacturer">Manufacturer</string>
    <string name="sort_property_name">Name</string>
    <string name="temperament_equal">Equal</string>
    <string name="temperament_label_name">Name</string>
    <string name="tuning_style_default">Default (%1$s)</string>
    <string name="free_plan_option_automatic_note_switching">Automatic note switching</string>
    <string name="free_plan_option_automatic_note_switching_description">Automatic note detection and switching</string>
    <string name="free_plan_option_mid_range_tuning">Tune sample notes only</string>
    <string name="free_plan_option_mid_range_tuning_description">Tuning functionality for select sample notes only, mostly in the mid-range of the piano. Evaluate if a piano is roughly in tune using the graph at the bottom</string>
    <string name="plan_free_subtitle">for evaluation</string>
    <string name="plan_free_title">Free version</string>
    <string name="plan_plus_subtitle">for piano enthusiasts</string>
    <string name="plan_plus_title">Plus version</string>
    <string name="plan_pro_subtitle">for professional piano tuners</string>
    <string name="plan_pro_title">Pro version</string>
    <string name="plus_plan_option_calibrate_device">Calibrate device</string>
    <string name="plus_plan_option_calibrate_device_description">Calibrate device to an external frequency source</string>
    <string name="plus_plan_option_change_a_frequency">Change from A=440</string>
    <string name="plus_plan_option_change_a_frequency_description">Tune to frequency standards other than A=440</string>
    <string name="plus_plan_option_tune_entire_piano">Tune the entire piano</string>
    <string name="plus_plan_option_tune_entire_piano_description">Tuning functionality for the entire piano (not just the mid-range)</string>
    <string name="plus_plan_option_unequal_temperament">Unequal temperament</string>
    <string name="plus_plan_option_unequal_temperament_description">Choose from a selection of historical temperaments or create your own</string>
    <string name="pro_plan_option_everything_from_plus">Everything from Plus</string>
    <string name="pro_plan_option_everything_from_plus_description">See Plus version</string>
    <string name="pro_plan_option_pitch_raise">Pitch raise (rough tuning)</string>
    <string name="pro_plan_option_pitch_raise_description">Pitch raise functionality that calculates overshoot for a \'rough\' tuning (for pianos that are extremely flat)</string>
    <string name="pro_plan_option_tuning_files">Save/load tuning files</string>
    <string name="pro_plan_option_tuning_files_description">Save and load multiple tuning files so a piano doesn\'t need to be re-measured each time it is tuned</string>
    <string name="pro_plan_option_tuning_styles">Customize tuning styles</string>
    <string name="pro_plan_option_tuning_styles_description">Create custom tuning curves by adjusting interval weighting and stretch</string>

    <string name="color_scheme_note_name">Note name</string>
    <string name="color_scheme_note_name_background">Note name background</string>
    <string name="color_scheme_rings">Rings</string>
    <string name="color_scheme_strobe_wheels">Strobe wheels</string>
    <string name="color_scheme_strobe_background">Strobe background</string>
    <string name="color_scheme_dial_markings">Dial markings</string>
    <string name="color_scheme_needle">Needle</string>
    <string name="color_scheme_graph_background">Graph background</string>
    <string name="color_scheme_tuning_curve_line">Tuning curve line</string>
    <string name="color_scheme_tuning_curve_dots">Tuning curve dots</string>
    <string name="color_scheme_inharmonicity_line">Inharmonicity line</string>
    <string name="color_scheme_inharmonicity_dots">Inharmonicity dots</string>
    <string name="color_scheme_spectrum_line">Spectrum line</string>
    <string name="color_scheme_current_note_indicator">Current note indicator</string>
    <string name="color_scheme_menu_main_color">Menu main color</string>
    <string name="color_scheme_menu_text">Menu text</string>
    <string name="color_scheme_back_panel">Back panel</string>
    <string name="color_scheme_top_panel">Top panel</string>
    <string name="color_scheme_auto_step_lock">Auto/Step/Lock</string>
    <string name="color_scheme_auto_step_lock_land">Auto/Step/Lock (land)</string>
    <string name="tone_player_duration_dialog_title">Seconds to play tone</string>
    <string name="dialog_tone_player_volume_and_leveling">Volume &amp; Leveling</string>
    <string name="tone_player_treble_bass_cutoff">Treble/Bass cutoff</string>
    <string name="tone_player_main_volume">Main Volume</string>
    <string name="tone_player_bass_volume">Bass\nVolume</string>
    <string name="tone_player_treble_volume">Treble\nVolume</string>

    <string name="status_tuning_curve_locked">Tuning curve locked</string>
    <string name="status_tuning_curve_unlocked">Recalculating tuning</string>
    <string name="status_note_change">Note %1$s</string>
    <string name="note_naming_local">Local</string>
    <string name="interval_weights_narrow_intervals">Narrow intervals</string>
    <string name="interval_weights_wide_intervals">Wide intervals</string>
    <string name="tuning_style_chart_current">Current</string>
    <string name="tuning_style_chart_default">Default</string>
    <string name="tuning_style_category_custom">Custom</string>
    <string name="pitch_raise_error_not_enough_data">Not enough note data for pitch raise!</string>

    <string name="app_plan_lock_free">(Free)</string>
    <string name="app_plan_lock_plus">(Plus)</string>
    <string name="app_plan_lock_pro">(Pro)</string>

    <string name="dialog_do_not_show_again">Don\'t show again</string>
    <string name="dialog_tone_generator_active_title">Tone generator</string>
    <string name="dialog_tone_generator_active_message">Tone generator is now active. Because the microphone is still on, please use headphones with the volume at a safe level and lock the tuning curve.</string>
    <string name="dialog_timed_play_once_title">Timed vs. Play once</string>
    <string name="dialog_timed_play_once_message">The tone generator has two modes:\n\n· <b>Timed mode</b> plays a tone for a set duration each time you time you switch notes. Long-press on the stopwatch button to adjust the time.\n\n· <b>Continuous mode</b> will play each tone constantly until you change notes but won\'t repeat tones if you later return to recently tuned notes. Consider using this mode for non-linear tuning sequences like tuning the middle string of a new note before the outer strings of the previous note (for instance tuning with a strip mute or leapfrogging two mutes).</string>
    <string name="dialog_tone_generator_leveling_title">Volume &amp; Leveling</string>
    <string name="dialog_tone_generator_leveling_message">Use these settings to fine-tune the volume for the treble and bass and compensate for frequency response differences between headphones. The up-and-down sliders adjust the volume level; the horizontal sliders adjust the range of notes affected by the volume sliders.</string>
</resources>